I...
Apology
from an
Armed
Detective
Agency
Member
Apology
from an
Armed
Detective
Agency
Member
Tanizaki
Junichirou
す　す…
I... I...
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
I'm so sorry!
すんませんでした
Huh?
Even thought it was just your exam,
試験の為とはいえ　随分と失礼なことを…
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
I was so rude to you.
My name is Tanizaki Junichirou.
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
ボクの名前は谷崎潤一郎　探偵社で助手のような仕事をしています
I work as an assistant of sorts at the agency.
Please, it's all right.
いやいや　気になさらずに
He's really not a bad person.
意外といい人だ　この人
そんで　こっちが…
And this is—
妹のナオミですわ
His little sister, Naomi.
Y-You're siblings?!
きょっ　兄妹ですか
その割には　髪や顔がそんなに似てないような…
I'm not sure I see a family resemblance.
Oh?
あら　お疑い？
You doubt us?
Of course we're blood related siblings.
勿論　血の繋がった実の兄妹ですわ　と・く・に
We're quite similar, especially this part.
この辺なんてほんっとそっくりぃ　ねぇ
Right, brother?
兄様ぁ
Oh, but...
いや　でも…
いやいやいやいやいや…
Don't pursue this line of
inquiry with them too far.
こいつらに関しては深く追求するな
お兄様ぁ　可愛らしい
Er, okay.
Atsushi reads
between the lines
あ…はい
In any event, brat,
ともかくだ小僧　貴様も今日から武装探偵社が一隅
ちょっと待っ…
もっとですか
today you have joined the ranks
of the Armed Detective Agency.
いてててててっ
兄様　ナオミ頑張ります　どうです…
Never be a burden to anyone,
nor shame the Agency's good name.
故に周りに迷惑を振り撒き
社の看板を汚す真似はするな
The rest of us are sworn
to that, at least.
俺も他のみんなも　そのことだけは徹底している
Right, Dazai?
なあ　太宰
か弱く華奢なこの指で　私の首を絞めてくれないか
Would you strangle me with these
fragile, delicate fingers?
Are you shaming the Agency's name already!?
云ってる傍から社の看板を汚すな
You bastard! Don't bother asking for
her help all the time!
貴様という奴はいつもいつも　尚彼女の手を借りるまでもないわ
俺のごつい指でお前の首を絞めてやる
I'll wring your neck with my own bony fingers!
そういえば　お二人は探偵社に入る前は何をしてたんですか
By the way,
Two Seniors
Shaming
the Agency's
Good Name
what did you two do
before you joined the Agency?
Uh, no real meaning behind
that question, by the way.
特に意味はないんですけど
中ててごらん
Take a guess.
Huh?
Oh, it's a game we often play.
なにね　定番のゲームなのだよ
The rookie tries to guess his
seniors' former occupations.
新入りは先輩の前の職業を中てるのさ
Well, it's part of their training
as detectives.
まっ　探偵修業の一環でもある
Tanizaki-san and Naomi-san... were students?
谷崎さんとナオミさんは…学生さん？
Oh, bingo.
中った　すごーい
I'm impressed.
どうしておわかりに
How did you know?
I heard you're a part-time worker,
ナオミさんはバイトだって聞いてたし
and I thought you might still
be a student given your uniform.
制服姿からして　現役の学生さんかなって
Tanizaki-san seems near
me in age, so... just a hunch.
谷崎さんのほうは齢が近そうだし　勘です
Honesty is a virtue.
正直でよろしい
じゃあ　国木田君は？
What about Kunikida-kun?
Who cares about what I used to be?!
俺の前職などどうでもいい
Public worker?
公務員…お役所勤めとか
An official?!
Close.
惜しい
彼は元々教師だよ　数学の先生だ
He was a teacher.
A math teacher.
Huh...
Of course you'd use Euler's formula here!
ここはｘの累乗を使うに決まっているだろォー
なんか物凄く納得
I can totally see that.
It's all in the past!
昔の話だ　思い出したくもない
I don't even want to think about it.
What about me, then?
じゃ　私は？
太宰さん？
You, Dazai-san?
Yes, me.
そう　私
Dazai-san was...
太宰さんは…
It's no good.
駄目だ　全く想像がつかない
I have no idea.
Don't bother, brat.
無駄だ　小僧
His former profession is one of the seven
mysteries of the Armed Detective Agency.
武装探偵社七不思議の一つなのだ　こいつの前職は
The first person to get it
right receives a reward, right?
確か最初に中てた人に賞金が出るんですよね
A reward?
賞金！？
That's right.
そうなんだよ　誰も中てられなくて賞金が膨れ上がってる
No one's been able to guess right,
so the reward's just ballooned.
膨れ上がった…
Ballooned...
Reward!
賞金
B-By the way,
ち…ちなみにその膨れ上がった賞金というのは如何ほどですか
just how much has this reward
ballooned to, exactly?
700,000 yen in all.
総額七十万
Seven hundred grand?!
ななじゅうまん
Oh!
The man
has a fire
lit under
him ——
The man
has a fire
lit under
him ——
S-So if I get it right, I can claim it?
あ…中ったら貰えるんですね　本当に本当ですね
Currently
penniless.
at the thought
of a 700,000
reward
at the thought
of a 700,000
reward
Are you actually serious?!
A suicide advocate is true to his word.
自殺主義者に二言はないよ
Atsushi-kun looks ecstatic.
敦君　目の色が変わってる
凄い気迫ですわ
His determination is admirable.
Seven hundred grand will be mine!
七十万　いただきます
Speculator?
相場師
違う
No.
作家
Writer?
外れ
Nope!
勤め人
Office worker?
外れ
Wrong!
研究職
Researcher!
ちがーう
No.
弁護士？
Lawyer?
ノーッ
No!
新聞記者とか
Journalist?
ブー
Boo.
大工さんだ
Carpenter!
違いまーす
Nope.
占い師
Fortune teller!
ちがーう
No.
パイロット
Pilot!
外れ
Wrong.
They're all random...
通訳
Interpreter!
出鱈目だ
ノンノン
Non, non!
Yeah...
板前さん
Japanese Chef.
ブー
Booo.
ですわね
じゃ　医者？
They really are.
Doctor?
No way.
いえ
神主
Shinto priest!
外れー
No!
役者
Actor!
ちがーう　けど…
No! But...
That's flattering.
役者は照れるねぇ～
I bet you were just wandering
around doing nothing.
どうせ何もせずにふらふらしていただけなのだろう
違うよ
Nope.
この件で私は嘘はつかない
I would never lie about this.
Do you yield, Atsushi-kun?
降参かな　敦君
Then you can take the check.
じゃあ　ここの払いはよろしくね
What?
持ち合わせがないなら　付けが利くよぉ
If you can't pay right now,
you can start a tab.
なんといっても　探偵社御用達のお店「うずまき」だからね
After all, it's the
Agency's go-to restaurant,
the Vortex.
Yes, this is Tanizaki.
はい　谷崎です
Yes, okay.
はい
はい　わかりました
Got it.
We have a job?
依頼か
Yes.
はい　依頼人の方は既に事務所のほうに
The client's already at the Agency.
Well, it's time to work.
さあ　仕事の時間だ
Let's save the guessing
game for another time.
私の過去の職業中てゲームは　また次の機会に
そ
の
重
い
足
を
膝
前
へ
導
く
sono omoi ashi o hiza o mae ni michibiku
That feeling pulls your feet onward,
その重い足を膝を前へ導く
负
责
人
Maki
负责人
chikara nanda tte Go ahead to
Telling you to go ahead towards a new power.
力
は
何
だ
っ
て
Go
ahead
問
う
力は何だって Go ahead 問う
君
の
中
に
生
じ
る
衝
動
は
treasure
kimi no naka ni shoujiru shoudou wa Treasure
That impulse born within you is a treasure!
君の中に生じる衝動はtreasure
honmon ka nisemono ka tsureteike yo
Whether it's real or fake, just take it along!
日
听
Cc.
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
本
物
か
偽
物
か
つ
れ
て
行
け
よ
日听
Cc.
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
本物か偽物か つれて行けよ
kuusou no kanata notte boku no mata mo taemai yo
Straddling the limits of this fantasy, my legs probably won't last,
空
想
の
彼
方
ま
で
僕
の
中
怠
慢
よ
空想の彼方まで 僕の中の怠慢よ
soredemo ii yo yume demo
But that's just fine, even if it's only a dream.
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
さ
ら
っ
て
も
い
よ
夢
で
も
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
さらってもいいよ 夢でも
todokisou de todokanai Make some noise
It seems within reach, but somehow too far off, so make some noise!
届
き
そ
う
で
届
か
な
い
make
some
noise
届きそうで届かない make some noise
kuukyo na nichijou wa kagayakidasu noka
Are these empty days gonna start shining bright?
空
虚
な
日
常
は
輝
き
出
す
の
か
空虚な日常は輝き出すのか
吐
き
出
す
よ
う
に
し
て
前
に
漕
げ
ば
hakidasu you ni shite mae ni mae ni kogeba
If we push on through like we're about to hurl,
吐き出すようにして前に前に漕げば
bokura no mirai wa kasoku shiteyuku darou
I'm sure our future will start to pick up speed!
僕
ら
の
未
来
は
加
速
し
て
い
く
だ
ろ
う
僕らの未来は加速していくだろう
今
こ
の
時
が
止
ま
る
と
し
て
も
ima kono toki ga tomaru to shitemo kono kokyuu made
Even if this moment in time becomes frozen,
今この時が止まるとしても
こ
の
呼
吸
ま
で
止
め
ら
れ
は
し
な
い
さ
この呼吸まで止められはしないさ
tomerare wa shinai sa kudaranai gohoubi mada?
There's no stopping this breath, so where's my worthless reward?
く
だ
ら
な
い
くだらない
ご
褒
美
ま
だ
？
ご褒美まだ？
So...
えーっと　調査のご依頼と伺っておりますが
You've mentioned that you'd like
to request an investigation,
いったいどのようなご用件でしょうか
but what manner of investigation
are we speaking of here?
Beautiful.
美しい
You're a lady as ephemeral and
elegant as a lotus blossom.
睡蓮の花の如き果敢なく　そして可憐なお嬢さんだ
Would you be willing to join me
in a double suicide—
どうか私と心中していただけないだァ…
What?
Ah.
Apologies for the disturbance.
お騒がせしました　気になさらずに
Don't worry.
Please disregard what just happened.
今のは忘れて　続けてください
Please continue.
Regarding my request...
それで依頼のお話なのですが
Y-Yes?
はい？
Wow.
凄い　この状態で普通に続きを始めた
She's managing to carry on as
though everything's normal.
Well, it seems there's
recently been a group of
実は我が社のビルヂングの裏手に最近よからぬ輩が屯しているようなのです
unsavory people loitering in
my company building's back alley.
よからぬ輩とは？
And by unsavory, you mean...
襤褸を纏った連中のようです
They appear to be dressed in rags.
Some of them have been heard
speaking a foreign language.
中には聞き慣れない異国の言葉を話す者もいるとか
そいつは
They must be smugglers or some such.
密輸業者の類だろう
心中…
The military police may police all they want,
軍警がいくら取り締まっても船蟲のように涌いてくる
but they keep multiplying
like rats on a ship.
They're inevitable in a port town.
港湾都市の宿業だな
Right.
ええ　無法の輩という証拠さえあれば　軍警に掛け合えます
If we had evidence that
they're running afoul of the law,
we could ask the military police.
So...
ですから…
You want us to investigate the
place and get that evidence.
現場を張って証拠を掴め…か
Brat.
小僧
Huh?
You will go.
お前が行け
What?!
It's a simple stakeout job.
ただ見張るだけの簡単な仕事だ
Besides, smugglers are mostly harmless.
それに密輸業者は　大抵逃げ足だけが取り得の無害な連中だ
They're usually only good
at making a break for it.
It's the perfect first job for you.
お前の初仕事には丁度いい
でも…
But...
Tanizaki, go with him.
谷崎　一緒に行ってやれ
兄様が行くなら　ナオミも随いて行きますわぁ～
If he's going, I'm going, too!
Nakajima
Atsushi
Rookie
Detective
Nervous
about
his first job.
Nakajima
Atsushi
Rookie
Detective
Nervous
about
his first job.
Hey, brat.
おい　小僧
It's not that I lack sympathy for
your misfortunate, undeserved life.
不運かつ不幸なお前の人生に　些かの同情がないわけでもない
As such, I'll give you a hint
for surviving in this city.
故に　この街で生きるコツを一つだけ教えてやる
Don't run into him.
こいつには遭うな　遭ったら逃げろ
If you do, run.
Who is he?
この人は…
マフィアだよ
A mafioso.
Though we call them that because
we know nothing else.
尤も　他に呼び方がないから　そう呼んでるだけだけどね
They're a vicious mob
who claims the port as their territory.
港を縄張りにする兇悪な犯罪組織
They're called the Port Mafia.
奴らは「ポート・マフィア」と呼ばれている
They're the most dangerous gang in
this city's underground.
この街の黒社会で最も危険な連中だ
中でもその写真の男は
Of them, the one in this photo
is a very dangerous man beyond
even the Agency's reach.
この探偵社のメンバーでも手に負えない危険な奴だ
何故危険なんですか
Why is he dangerous?
Because he's gifted.
そいつが異能力者だからだ
His ability happens to be of the ruthless
sort designed for slaughter.
然も殺戮に特化した頗る残忍な異能力で
Not even the cops
stand a chance against him.
軍警でも手に負えん
I wouldn't want to fight him, either.
俺でも奴と戦うのは御免だ
What's his name?
この男の名は？
It's Akutagawa.
芥川だ
I found a bag on the ground.
道に鞄が落ちていました　遺失物かと
I think its owner lost it.
Ah, lost and found.
ああ　落し物ですね
Then if you could fill out this form...
じゃあ　この書類に詳細を…
Hm?
おや　あんたどっかで…
I've seen you before.
流石　もう看破なされたか
That's impressive.
I've already been found out.
まさか　こいつ手配書の…
Wait, is he the wanted fugitive?!
Stop!
動くな
The military police of this
city are a distinguished force.
矢張りこの街の軍警は頗る優秀だ
Excuse me,
あのう　道をお尋ねしたい…
could help me find—
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Abi:lity
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Abi:lity
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Wanted:
Akutagawa
Ryuunosuke
Ability:
Rashoumon
Episode 3
Yokohama Gangster Paradise
Done.
終わった　次は？
What's next?
Wow Wow Yeah
It takes two to commit double suici—
心中は一人ではできない
Hey, Dazai.
おい　太宰　仕事はどうした
What about the job?
I'm waiting for a sign from above.
天の啓示待ち
Huh?
二人ならできるぅ
With two, you can...
Double-suicide... Double-suicide...
心中　心中　心中心中　Let's go　心中…
That's scary, all right.
それは脅かされましたね
It's not funny.
笑い事じゃないですよ
All this talk about vicious
mafia and how you can die,
兇悪なマフィアとか　死ぬかと
I'm not sure I'm cut out for this.
矢っ張り途んでもない処に入っちゃったな
まぁまぁ　ボクでも続けられるくらいだから　大丈夫ですって
Well, even I've been able to manage.
You'll be fine.
でも　谷崎さんも「異能力者」なんですよね
But you're also gifted, right?
僕の役に立たない能力とは違う
Your ability must be different
from my own useless one.
I wouldn't set your expectations too high.
あんまり期待しないでくださいよ　戦闘向きじゃないですから
My ability's not suited for combat.
兄様の能力　素敵ですよ　ナオミあれ大好き
You have a wonderful ability.
I love it.
Stop, Naomi.
止めなよ　ナオミ　こんな処で
Not here.
あら　口応え？
Oh, are you talking back to me?
I wonder what mouth's saying
such cheeky things.
生意気な口はど・の・く・ちかしらぁ
We're here.
着きました
Huh?
This way.
こちらです
It's kind of creepy.
なんか鬼魅の悪い処ですね
That's strange.
おっかしいなぁ　本当にここなんですか
Is this really the right place?
Um...
えっとー…
樋口です
The name's Higuchi.
樋口さん　密輸業者というのは臆病な連中です
Higuchi-san.
Smugglers are a cowardly bunch.
They'll always have an escape route.
だから必ず逃げ道を用意します
But this is a dead end.
ここ　袋小路ですよね
If anyone came after them
from there,
捕り方がそっちから来たら　逃げ場がない
they'd have nowhere to run.
That's right.
その通りです
I apologize. I led you into a trap.
失礼とは存じますが
嵌めさせていただきました
My real target was you!
私の目的は　貴方がたです
Port Mafia:
Higuchi Ichiyou
Akutagawa-senpai.
芥川先輩
芥川？
Akutagawa?!
予定通り　捕らえました
I have them, as planned.
Excellent.
重畳
I'll be there in five.
五分で向かう
She's...
こいつ…
ポートマフィア
...with the Port Mafia!
こいつ…
She's...
ポートマフィア
...with the Port Mafia!
Brother... Are you okay?
兄…様　大…丈夫？
ナオミ
Naomi?
Naomi!
ナオミ！
God, what should I do?
どうしよう
Oh, right! Tourniquet!
そうだ　止血帯
敦君　止血帯持ってない？
Atsushi-kun, do you have
a tourniquet on you?!
いや先ずは傷口を洗って…
No, first, I must clean the wound...
No!
ああ違う　与謝野先生に診せなきゃあ
I have to get her to Dr. Yosano.
…医務室まで運ばないと
We... We have to take her to the infirmary!
Atsushi-kun, get her legs!
敦君　足持って
My investigations have already revealed
that you are a non-combatant member.
貴方が戦闘要員でないことは調査済みです
Let's have you follow the noble
princess to the afterlife.
健気な姫君の後を追っていただきましょうか
What?
あ？
チンピラ如きが
You two-bit thug...
なっ
How dare you hurt Naomi!
よくもナオミを傷つけたねー
Ability: Light Snow!
異能力
「細雪」
Snow at this time of year?
この季節に雪？
Atsushi-kun, stay far back.
敦君　奥に退がっているんだ
This one... is mine to kill!
こいつはボクが　殺すっ
What?
なに
My Light Snow ability
ボクの「細雪」は　雪の降る空間凡てをスクリーンに変える
transforms the entire space
with snowfall into a screen.
なんだと
What?
I have overlaid the background
scenery onto my image.
ボクの姿の上に背後の風景を「上書き」した
もうお前にボクの姿は見えない
You can't see me anymore!
姿は見えずとも弾は中る
I may not be able to see you,
but bullets can still hit you!
Wrong.
大外れ
Die!
死んでしまえ
Fear death.
死を惧れよ
Fear slaughter.
殺しを惧れよ
Those who desire death
死を望む者　等しく死に
have an equal desire to die.
Therefore...
望まるるが故に
Don't run into him!
こいつには遭うな
If you do, run!
遭ったら逃げろ
It's nice to meet you.
お初にお目にかかる
I am Akutagawa,
僕は芥川　そこな小娘と同じポートマフィアの狗
one the Port Mafia's dogs, as is she.
Akutagawa-senpai!
芥川先輩
I can handle this myself.
ここは私一人でも…
I believe my orders were to
take the weretiger alive!
人虎は生け捕りとの命の筈
And yet here you are, gunning everyone down.
片端から撃ち殺してどうする
You useless bitch!
この役立だずめ　退がっていろ
Stand down.
I'm sorry.
すみません
Take the weretiger alive?
人虎は生け捕り？
What are you after?
あんた達はいったい…
もとより僕らの目的は貴様一人なのだ　人虎
My target has always been you
and you alone, weretiger.
Your fellow agents lying there
just got caught in the crossfire.
そこに転がるお仲間は　いわば貴様の巻添え
This is because of me?
僕の所為でみんなが…
然り
Indeed.
That is your karma, weretiger.
それが貴様の業だ　人虎
You cause misfortune for everyone
around you, just by living.
貴様は生きてるだけで周囲の人間を損なう
Get out, you failure!
出ていけ　穀潰し
The world would be a better place
どこぞで野垂れ死んだほうが世間様の為よ
if you'd just die in a ditch somewhere!
You'll never find a place where you belong!
いや　天下のどこにもお前の居場所などありはせん
My karma?
僕の業？
Ability:
異能力
Rashoumon.
「羅生門」
I missed on purpose that time, of course.
勿論今のはわざと外した
But my Rashoumon has poor taste.
だが僕の「羅生門」は悪食　凡るものを喰らう
It devours anything and everything.
I intend to capture you alive,
but if you continue to resist,
生け捕りが目的だが　抵抗するならば
I'll take your leg next.
次はお前の脚を奪う
Why...
何故…どうして僕が…
Why me?
Is this my fault, too?
それも僕の所為？
Do I make everyone around me
suffer just by living?
僕が生きてるだけでみんなを不幸にするのか
あ…敦君
A... Atsushi-kun.
Run, Atsushi-kun.
逃げろ　敦君
They're still alive.
二人ともまだ息がある
Today you have joined the ranks
of our Armed Detective Agency.
貴様も今日から武装探偵社が一隅
Never be a burden to anyone,
nor shame the Agency's good name.
社の看板を汚す真似はするな
玉砕か　詰らぬ
Choosing death over submission,
how tiresome.
That move wasn't half bad.
今の動きは中々よかった
But in the end, it was a fool's last stand.
しかし所詮は愚者の蛮勇
I told you.
云っただろう
My black beast is indiscriminate.
僕の黒獣は悪食
It devours anything and everything.
凡るものを喰らう
It consumed the very space bullets
were attempting to cross to reach me.
銃弾の飛来し着弾するまでの空間そのものを喰い削った
Neither spears nor flames can reach me
槍も炎も空間が断絶していれば　僕までは届かぬが道理
without a space to traverse.
How is anyone supposed to attack him, then?
そんなの　攻撃の仕様がないじゃないか
And I am a man who keeps his word.
そして僕　約束は守る
Quit crying, brat!
泣くのを止めろ　餓鬼め
Only children who have parents
to care of them
詮なく泣いて許されるのは　負うてくれる親のある児のみ
are allowed to cry without reservation!
親にも捨てられたような者に　泣く資格などない
A child abandoned by his parents
has no license to cry!
That's right.
そうだ
I've been abandoned countless
times over the course of my life.
僕はずっと見捨てられながら生きてきた
I was never allowed to cry,
泣くことも許されず　誰からも認められず
no one ever accepted me,
and I never had a place I could call home.
人間としての居場所もなく
And yet, I...
それでも僕は…
なんだと
What?
His right leg regenerated.
右脚が再生した？
This is how it should be.
そうこなくては
Akutagawa-senpai!
芥川先輩
Stand down, Higuchi!
退がっていろ　樋口
なに
What?
Senpai!
先輩
You!
おのれー
The bullets can't penetrate its skin.
銃弾が通らない
Rashoumon:
「羅生門・顎」
Agito!
生け捕りの筈が
I was supposed to take you alive.
This is...
これは…
So I just ripped apart a mirage? Then,
今切り裂いたのは虚像か　では…
Rashoumon:
「羅生門・叢」
Murakumo!
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
Okay, that's enough!
はーい　そこまでー
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
What?
You're one of the detectives.
貴方は探偵社の…
Why are you here?
何故ここに
I'm the type who can't stop thinking about
what a beautiful lady might be up to.
美人さんの行動は気になっちゃう質でねー
こっそり聞かせてもらった
I decided to secretly listen in.
Impossible.
まさか
Back then...
あの時に
You had already seen through
my plans then.
では最初から私の計画を見抜いて
Come on, wake up, Atsushi-kun.
ほらほら起きなさいよ　敦君
三人も負ぶって帰るの嫌だよ私
I don't want to carry three
people back at the same time.
You think we'll let you go alive?
生きて帰すと思っているのか
Don't, Higuchi.
止めろ樋口　お前では勝てぬ
You can't win.
But, Akutagawa-senpai...
芥川先輩　でも
Dazai-san, we'll retreat for this round.
太宰さん　今回は退きましょう
しかし　人虎の身柄は必ず僕らポートマフィアがいただく
But the weretiger will be
the Port Mafia's someday.
Why?
なんで
Simple enough.
簡単なこと
That weretiger has a bounty
on him from the black market.
その人虎には闇市で懸賞金が懸かっている
The bounty sum is seven billion yen.
賞金の額は七十億
Now, that's very generous.
それは随分と景気のいい話だねー
We'll pay a visit to your
Agency at a later time.
探偵社にはいずれまた伺います
The Port Mafia will claim that seven billion.
ポートマフィアは必ずその七十億を奪う
Is that a declaration of war
on the Armed Detective Agency?
では　武装探偵社と戦争かい
Try it... if you dare.
やってみたまえよ
やれるものなら
You're a small-scale operation,
零細企業如きが
whereas we are this city's
darkness made incarnate.
我々はこの街の暗部そのもの　この街の政治　経済のことごとくに根を張る
We have connections in this city's
politics and economy at every level.
An agency with a dozen or so operatives
たかが十数人の探偵社如き　三日と待たず事務所ごと灰と消える
will become ashes along with your
office in three days' time.
No one has opposed us and lived.
我々に逆らって　生き残った者などいないのだぞ
I know all that.
知ってるよ　そのくらい
然り
Indeed.
You know that better than anyone
外の誰より　貴方はそれを承知している
being an ex-Port Mafia member, Dazai-san.
元ポートマフィアの太宰さん
boku ga boku de irareru
I was searching for the reason
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
riyuu o sagashiteita
why I'm able to stay as I am.
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
anata no mune no naka de
If there's a version of me
ikiteiru boku ga iru no naraba
that exists in your heart,
kurayami mo nagai sakamichi mo
Then even if darkness looms on this rocky road,
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
koeteikeru you na boku ni nareru hazu
I'll be able to find the way to the new me.
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
sorezore ni ima o aruiteru bokura ga waraeru you ni
So that we can keep smiling in our own moments,
ikiteiru imi o tashikameainagara susumeru you ni
So that we can explore the meaning of life together,
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
あなたがあなたでいれるように
anata ga anata de ireru you ni
So that you can stay how you are.
kanashimi ni kurete anata no namida ga koboreru toki
Whenever you're overcome by grief, and tears flow,
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
samishisa ni afureta kokoro ga shibondeku toki
Whenever your heart floods with loneliness and you waste away,
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに
boku no namae o yondekureta mitai ni
Just as you once called out mine.
I heard, brat.
聞いたぞ　小僧
There's a bounty on your head to the tune
of seven billion on the black market.
お前　裏社会の闇市で七十億の懸賞首になってるらしいな
Wh-Wh-What should I do?
ど…どどどうしよう
Maybe the Port Mafia will
come raid the Agency.
ポートマフィアがこの探偵社に押し寄せてくるかも
But why me?
でも　どうして僕が
You caused this.
お前が招き入れた事態だ
Think about what you can do.
自分ができることを考えておけ
What I can do?
僕にできることって
Next time on Bungou Stray Dogs, episode 4:
次回　「文豪ストレイドッグス」第四話
The Tragedy of the Fatalist.
Episode 4
The Tragedy of the Fatalist
「運命論者の悲み」